甜蜜日常 偶而浪一浪
♪ It's a sweet life, still a little messy. ♪
奇妙日常 惊喜一萝筐
♪ Magic life, full of surprises. ♪
迅捷日常
♪ Fast life ♪
瞧我宝石多时尚
♪ Gaze upon my gems! ♪
开心日常 朋友在身旁
♪ It's a fun life because we got each other. ♪
可爱日常
♪ It's a cute life. ♪
缤纷天地自己闯
♪ Living life in our own way! ♪
点滴一起来分享
♪ Come on grab a slice of cake. ♪
甜蜜 奇妙 迅捷 时尚 开心 可爱
♪ It's a sweet, magic, fast, posh, fun, cute ♪
小马日常
♪ Pony Life! ♪
每分每秒都难忘
♪ Fun in every bite.  ♪
友谊 彩虹 真的棒
♪ Friendship, rainbows, wuh-oh! ♪
甜蜜
♪ It's a sweet  ♪
奇妙
♪ Magic ♪
迅捷
♪ Fast ♪
时尚
♪ Posh ♪
开心
♪ Fun ♪
可爱
♪ Cut ♪
小马日常
♪ Pony Life! ♪
友谊
碰撞
我 大块头
I'm Bulk Biceps,
竞技精神的实体具现
the Spirit of Competition.
将带领大家观看今天的重头戏
Guiding you through today's Mane Event
体验这独一无二的
at the one, the only,
体育盛宴
SPORTACULAR SPECTACULAR!
现在是小马对小马
Looks like it's pony vs. pony.
骏马对骏马
Steed vs. steed.
美女对野兽
Beauty vs. beast.
开玩笑呢 因为我们都是美女
Aaand kidding, cuz we're all beauties.
我们也是野兽
And we're all beasts!
至少 我觉得不至于
Well I wouldn't go that far.
真希望我们能在同一支队伍
I wish we were playing on the same team!
这样就能一起赢了
That way we'd all win.
或者一起输
Or all lose!
只是说有这种可能嘛
I'm just saying it's possible.
朋友们也会希望我们全力以赴
Our friends would want us to give it our all.
无论输赢，我们都会尽力
Win or lose, we'll try our best.
非得分个胜负 让我好纠结
I'm sad that if we win, they lose.
反正我不想输
Well I don't want to lose.
怎么 你去试镜难道只是为了当个替角?
What?! You don't audition hoping to be the understudy.
她想说的是
What she's tryin' to say is that
哪怕我们要和朋友比赛
even though we're competin' against our pals,
我们也要拿出100%的实力
we gotta give it 100 percent.
甚至110%
Maybe 110 percent.
棒 接的好
Yeah nice catch!
我是说 接的不好?
I-I mean, bad catch?
哦 我没办法给她们加油
Ohh! I can't not cheer for them!
我们加油
Go us!
你们加油
Go them!
我们加油
Go us!
她们加油
Go them?
要是比赛过后她们还是朋友
It'll be amazing if these ponies make it through
那就真是太棒了
and are still friends after this.
好了 该回去干活了
Welp-- gotta get back to work.
魔药可不会自己填满柜子
Potions don't restock themselves.
不会吗?
They don't?!
吃灰吧
Eat my dust!
等等 作为专业厨师  我不能让大家吃灰
Wait, as a food professional I can't serve dust.
吃杯糕吧
Eat my cupcakes!
一切都变得清晰起来
Everything's coming into focus.
腾空3秒
Three seconds in the air,
10步一栏
ten paces per hurdle.
只要照计算行事 就能赢下赛跑
This race can be won using a calculated game plan!
哇 暮暮
Wow, Twi,
你重新定义了 "靠头脑比赛"
you give new meaning to getting your head in the game!
我来给你的比赛添点压力
I'm giving you a run for your money.
你是说 "让我很想吃蜂蜜" ?
You mean, run for my honey?
行吧 我不在乎 随便吧
Fine, I don't even care,like whatever...
我在终点线放一罐蜂蜜时 总能跑得更快
I always run faster when I plant a jar of honey at the finish line.
我可没把这点算进去
I did not calculate for that.
6名最强选手之间的最终比赛
The final round features the top six players
将进行的是 长桨比武
competing in the joust!
获胜队伍将加冕
The winning team will be crowned
体育盛宴冠军
Sportacular Spectacular champaculars!
她们会因为咱们是朋友就放水吗
Do you think they'll go easy on us 'cause we're friends?
她们并没有放慢速度 我们也不能
They haven't slowed down yet, so neither will we!
咱们还是得拿出110%的斗志
Let's still give 110 percent.
也许120%
Maybe 120 percent!
不许打我鬃毛
Gentle on the mane!
哎呀
Yikes!
太险了
That was too close!
只剩你和我了 伙计
It's just you and me, pard'ner.
好耶
Yeehaw!
我从没见过朋友之间这样激情碰撞
I've never seen friends competelike this against friends.
你们将竞技精神体现得淋漓尽致
They really get what the spirit of competition is all about.
嘿 那是我
Hey! That's me!
竞技精神的实体具现
The Spirit of Competition!
是是 那当然好啦
Yeah yeah that's great and all
但你至少先说说谁输谁赢
but you gotta tell us who won and who lost
好让我们回去继续做朋友
so we can get back to being friends!
在不同的队伍不代表你们就不是朋友了
Being on different teams doesn't mean you're not friends.
当你拿出全力比赛
By competing your hardest
你会让你的朋友也全力以赴
you push your friends to also play their best.
我觉得壮壮先生说得有道理
I think Mr. Biceps is onto something.
我们来时是朋友 走时也是朋友...
We came here as friends,we're gonna leave as friends...
那我们比赛时不也是朋友吗
Didn't we compete as friends?
实际上  比赛还剩5秒钟
In fact, there's five seconds left!
让我们全力拼搏吧
Let's give it our all.
130%全力
130 percent!
恭喜各位
Congratulations, ponies.
看来你们都是今天的总冠军
It looks like you're all champaculars today.
平局
It's a tie!
你们都是冠军
You're all champions!
获胜 好像也没什么不好
Winning. Not so bad.
谢幕
声歌
起来来来 来!
Get up up up up UP!
今天是最后一天 也就是说······
oday's the final day and that means...
今天有"体坛盛宴闭幕音乐剧"
it's the Sportacular Spectacular Musical Musakular show!
有音乐 有烟火
It's got music!  It's got fireworks!
还有其他内容
It's got other stuff!
所以 赶快起床 打起精神吧 大伙们
So rise and sparkle, everypony!
竞技精神的实体具现 大块头
The Spirit of Competition,Bulk Biceps,
为大家准备了精彩万分的表演
has an incredible performance planned for us!
我都等不及了
I CAN'T WAIT!
就不能让我们多睡一会儿吗
Can't we sleep just a little longer?
没们儿 小-马
No way, po-nay.
我们得早点赶到会场占个好座位
We need to get there early or we won't get good seats!
准备好了吗? 咱们走
Everypony ready? Let's go!
看吧 全场最棒的座位
See? Best seats in the house!
你们怎么睡得着的?
How are you ponies asleep?
这里充满了活力
The energy here is electric!
我的天啊 我们这美容觉睡了多久
My hoofness, how long were we beauty-resting?
也没多久 整个 白天而已
Oh, not long. Just all day.
音乐剧马上就开始了
The show'll begin any minute.
竞技精神的具现已经到场了
There's the Spirit of Competition now!
太好了 我正找你们呢
Oh good! Just the ponies I was looking for!
我需要你们
I need you!
好了 快说说这是怎么回事吧
Now what in tarnation is goin' on here?
我这几天深受触动
I've been so inspired by
因为我见证了你们在体坛盛宴上的表现
watching you compete here at the Sportacular Spectacular.
你们不仅是优秀的运动员
You are true sportsponies,
还是更优秀的好朋友
but even better friends!
你们让我领悟到 我也该去做一个好朋友
You've shown me that I need to be a better friend too.
交朋友可不容易
Because friendship can be hard,
但友谊值得为之付出一切
but it's what makes everything worthwhile.
你说的对
You said it!
所以我想，我为什么要在这里
So I thought, why am I here,
上演一场完美无缺
putting on a perfectly-executed,
毕生难遇的演出
once-in-a-lifetime show,
我应去跟我的老朋友兼老对手
when I should go make things right with my old pal,slash-rival
浩克•蹄筋  重归于好
Hulk Hamstrings
我刚才回忆杀了
I'm having a flashback.
这倒提醒我了 我得把我的绶带  让给你们
That reminds me! I-I gotta give my sash back.
给你小马们
To you ponies!
现在你们是竞技精神的实体具现了
You're the Spirits of Competition now!
等等 大块头先生
Wait, Mr. Biceps!
你的演出
Your show!
不 是你们的演出
No, your show.
你们赢来的
You earned it.
所以...... 闭幕式就交给你们了
Soooo... you're in charge of the closing ceremonies.
祝好运
Good luck!
我们什么都没有准备
We don't have anything prepared!
我们要唱些什么啊
What are we gonna sing?!
让我们 歌唱比赛
♪ A sooong about the games... ♪
以及友谊
♪ And friendshiiip... ♪
再加上魔法 如果时间够的···话
♪ And magic if we have tiiiiiiiime ♪
我是只出众小马
♪ I'm a standout pony ♪
永远的赢家
♪ a winner through and through ♪
但生活这出戏码
♪ But I'm just a one mare show ♪
不能少了你和她
♪ Without you and you ♪
还有你
And you!
没有朋友
♪ Without friends ♪
华美也只流于苍白
♪ I'm a lime without the light ♪
当我们凝成一团
♪ When we are together... ♪
更闪耀着光彩
♪ We shine extra bright! ♪
友谊并不简单
♪ It isn't always easy ♪
相处也会是考验
♪ Friendship can be hard ♪
珍视每个伙伴
♪ But for every friend I have ♪
用心维系浇灌
♪ I'd trot that extra yard ♪
我永远支持你
♪ I've always got your back ♪
奔向梦中目的地
♪ For any goal you dream ♪
无论相聚或分离
♪ Together or apart ♪
我们心都在一起
♪ We make the perfect team! ♪
遭遇瓶颈难闯过
♪ If you hit an obstacle ♪
我帮你找回执着
♪ I'll help ya stay on course ♪
朋友让你振作
♪ Cuz friends will cheer you on ♪
哪怕你只想把马头缩
♪ When you're a tiny horse! ♪
我们是小马
We're ponies!
友谊是妙药良方
♪ There are no rules to friendship ♪
有需要就别逞强
♪ Except help outwhen you are down ♪
不用魔药帮忙
♪ It doesn't take a potion ♪
也能让局势变样
♪ To turn the game around! ♪
友谊并不简单
♪ It isn't always easy ♪
相处也会是考验
♪ Friendship can be hard ♪
珍视每个伙伴
♪ But for every friend I have ♪
用心维系浇灌
♪ I'd trot that extra yard ♪
我永远支持你
♪ I always got your back ♪
奔向梦中目的地
♪ For any goal you dream ♪
无论相聚或分离
♪ Together or apart ♪
我们心都在一起
♪ We make the perfect team! ♪
有谁是属于友谊队的
Who here's on Team Friendship?
我们属于友谊队
We're on Team Friendship!
如果你别具一格
If there ain't no pony just like you,
那你属于友谊队
then you're on Team Friendship!
我们属于友谊队
We're on Team Friendship!
如果你表里如一 坚持自我 那么...
If you're yourself from the inside out then...
我们属于友谊队
We're on Team Friendship!
如果你愿意接见~你的头号粉丝 那么...
If you got to meet-n-gree-ee-eet your number one fan then...
我们属于友谊队
We're on Team Friendship!
如果你在大半夜溜进甜点屋
♪ If you sneak into Sugarcube Corner in the middle of the night ♪
直奔魔药小冰箱
♪ To restockthe potion fridge ♪
补充魔药 还和店里小马交朋友...
♪ Magic potions, friends with ponies working there...♪
然后你和上述小马
Then you come to an understanding
达成了共识
with those aforementioned ponies
那么
then
那么 我也属于友谊队
Then I'm on Team Friendship!
起跑线上燃斗志
♪ Step up to the starting line ♪
但友谊无名次
♪ But friendship's not a race ♪
齐头并进相扶持
♪ When I'm trotting next to you ♪
我们都是第一
♪ We're always in first plaaaaaaaa-aaaaaceeeee! ♪
对 我们就是
Yeah we are!
大家一起来
All together now!
友谊并不简单
♪ It isn't always easy ♪
相处也会是考验
♪ Friendship can be hard ♪
珍视每个伙伴
♪ But for every friend I have ♪
用心维系浇灌
♪ I'd trot that extra yard ♪
闪耀
♪ We shine ♪
我永远支持你
♪ I've always got your back ♪
光芒
♪ Shine bright ♪
奔向梦中目的地
♪ For any goal you dream ♪
更亮
♪ Brighter ♪
无论相聚或分离
♪ Together or apart ♪
光芒
♪ Shine bright ♪
我们心都在一起
♪ We make the perfect team! ♪
同绽放
♪ Together! ♪
闪耀
♪ We shine! ♪
光芒
♪ Shine bright! ♪
更亮
♪ Brighter! ♪
同绽放
♪ Together! ♪
光芒
♪ Shine bright! ♪
更亮
♪ Brighter! ♪
光芒
♪ Shine bright! ♪
同绽放
♪ Together! ♪
闪耀
♪ We shine! ♪
绽放
♪ Shine bright! ♪
友谊
♪ Brighter! ♪
聚气光芒
♪ Together... ♪
怎么样 很壮观吧
How's that for spectacular?
中文翻译绝大部分来自:
★放肆欧米嘎☆    薇紫天兰    隼鹰羽    田澄    S. Firefly
英文字幕来自: Yayponies
片源: Yayponies/Amazon RAW